Finding Aid for the Anaïs Nin Papers, ca. 1910-1977 LSC.2066
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Published Works by Anaïs Nin, 1932-1982; 1.25 Linear Feet
  Included are page proofs for vol.6 of The Diary of Anaïs Nin and erotica written by Nin in the 1940's. The erotica were subsequently published as The Delta of Venus.
  - The Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1955-1966 (vol.6). New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Incorporated, May 31, 1976.; Uncorrected proofs. 283pp. 14 × 27.2 cm. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Erotica, ca. 1940-1941, 1980, 1982; 1.0 linear ft. (13 folders)
    Erotica manuscripts written by Anaïs Nin and Japanese translations.
    - Anita, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript. 14 leaves. With title page and page numbering in Anaïs Nin's hand. (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Erotica is in folders 6-11 in this box and folders 1-5 in box 8. Most were published in Delta of Venus (New York & London: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich) [c1969, 1977]. During this period, Nin, Henry Miller, Caresse Crosby, Robert Duncan and others wrote erotica for an anonymous collector who paid them a dollar a page.
      For further information, see The Diary of Anaïs Nin, 1939-1944. Volume 3.
    - Artist model, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript, typescript(carbon). In black folder. 131 leaves. With title page and page numbering in Nin's hand, some proofreading marks in pencil. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Elena, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript, typescript(carbon). pp.1-199. A note on p.47 indicates a fragment missing. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Elena, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript, typescript(carbon). pp.200-393. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Hungarian adventurer, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript. In black folder. 66 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Includes the stories, "Mathilde," "Manuel," "The Ring."
    - Lilith, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript. 11 leaves. (Box 7, Folder 11)
      With title page and page numbering in Anaïs Nin's hand.
    - Linda, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript(carbon). In black folder. 47 leaves. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mallorca, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript. 15 leaves. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Marcel, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript(carbon). 93 leaves. With title page and page numbering in Anaïs Nin's hand. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Maryanne, [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript. 60 leaves. With title page and page numbering in Anaïs Nin's hand. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Two sisters,", [ca. 1940-1941].; Typescript. 28 leaves. With title page and page numbering in Anaïs Nin's hand. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Published in Little Birds, New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich [c1979].
    - Deruta obu Vinasu [Delta of Venus], Tokyo: Futami Shobo, 1980.; Dustjacket. 342pp. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Ritoru Bado [Little Birds], Tokyo: Fujimi Shobo, 1982.; Dustjacket. 230pp. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Presentation Copies, 1932, 1936; 0.25 Linear Feet
    Inscribed copies to John Meston.
    - Nin, Anaïs, D.H. Lawrence: An Unprofessional Study, Paris: Edward W. Titus, 1932.; 146pp. With some manuscript notations. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Presentation copy to John Meston.
    - Nin, Anaïs, The House of Incest, Paris: Siana Editions, [1936].; 89pp. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Presentation copy to John Meston, Paris, 1939.
      Copy number 147 of 249.
- Photographs
  - Joaquín Nin (José Joaquin Nin y Castellanos)., 1914 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Sepia tone photograph, 8-7/8" × 6-3/4", mounted on board.7/8" tear along top edge, 4-3/8" from left. TeartrPaper loss in upper right corner of mount. 1-1/2" tear along right side of mount, beginning 4-7/8" from top.
    Scope and Contents
    Photograph by Atelier Pajor, Paris. "= 1914 - Paris - " written under the photograph on the mount in an unidentified hand.